Sharan Kumar B () Featured

Tibco Developer seeking a challenging position in the field of Information Technology. Being an organized team player, I look forward to work in environments and projects which have an ample combination of design, programming and analysis



Current Designation: Senior Associate Consultant - IT Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Infosys Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: tibco,tibco bw,tibco ems,tibco administrator,tibco iprocess,tibco designer,mysql,Oracle,Mulesoft

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

6.8 years Experience in Software Development involving design, development, deployment and testing of Enterprise applications using TIBCO Suite of Products - TIBCO Business Works, TIBCO Designer, TIBCO EMS, Tibco BPM Studio, TIBCO Administrator.

Complete knowledge of EAI and BPM concepts, Design, Implementation and best practices.

Designed and developed EAI TIBCO Interfaces and services using TIBCO Business Works (5.x and 6.x) and TIBCO EMS (6.x,8.x).

Designed and developed BPM Workflows using Tibco AMX BPM Studio.

Expertise in using messaging standards such as JMS and TIBCO EMS for developing distributed applications.

Expertise in invoking and hosting web services using SOAP & REST.

Work Experience

Infosys as Senior Associate Consultant - IT

Nov 2018 to Till Date

1)6+ years Experience in Software Development involving design, development, deployment and testing of Enterprise applications using TIBCO Suite of Products - TIBCO Business Works, TIBCO Designer, TIBCO EMS, Tibco BPM Studio, TIBCO Administrator.

2)Complete knowledge of EAI and BPM concepts, Design, Implementation and best practices.

3)Designed and developed EAI TIBCO Interfaces and services using TIBCO Business Works (5.x and 6.x) and TIBCO EMS (6.x,8.x).

4)Designed and developed BPM Workflows using Tibco BPM Studio.

5)Expertise in using messaging standards such as JMS and TIBCO EMS for developing distributed applications.

6)Expertise in invoking and hosting web services using SOAP and REST.

HCL Technologies as Consultant

Nov 2016 to Nov 2018

Worked on Tibco AMX BPM, BW 5 and BW 6 and administrator. Client : One of the largest pharmaceutical companies in USA

Role : Tibco Developer Responsibilites :

Collecting Bussiness Requirements and Creating Technical Specification document.

2) AMX BPM Coding: Creating Organization model, Bussiness Object model, Workflow project(BPM Developer project). Creating Process interfaces, Bussiness processes, Bussiness services and service processes.

BW Coding: Exposing Rest Services which invokes AMX BPM Soap API's for any Read/Write Operations.

- 3) Unit Testing: Preparing Unit test document. Testing of work flows is done using Tibco Openspace. Testing the exposed Rest Services using Postman.
- 4) Delivering the code using SVN Version control system.
- 5) Building DAA, Creating Resource templates, Deploying, Upgading and Managing applications.
- 6) Building EAR, Creating profiles, deploying and Managing applications.
- Working on defects raised by testers.

TCS as Systems Engineer Mar 2014 to Nov 2016

Project undergone in TCS

Worked on Tibco BW, EMS and Administrator.

Client: One of the leading providers of Credit Cards in USA.

Responsibilities:

Creating Detailed level design (DLD), Low level design (LLD) and Mapping sheet.

Coding creating Processes, schemas, abstract WSDL, concrete WSDL using service activity and adding global variables as per requirement.

Unit testing: Preparing test cases and executing it in designer. Used Jmeter and SOAP UI for testing.

Delivering the code using RTC version control system.

Building an EAR, Deploying and managing business components in dev environment.

Providing fixes for defects raised during testing.

Supporting the application in Dev/Sit/UAT/Load enviornment.

Other Responsibilities:

Worked on migration of version control system from clear case to RTC by creating components, delivering code from clear case to RTC and Nexus build of these components.

Working on regression issues.

Running all critical services using Jmeter after deployment in dev environment.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
TIBCO BW	5.x, 6.x	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Tibco BPM	4.x	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TIBCO EMS	6.x, 8.x	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TIBCO ADMINISTRATOR	5.x	2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TIBCO IPROCESS	11.x	2020	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Oracle 11g, MySql, Postgree		2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Java, JavaScript, SQL/PL-SQL		2020	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
TEA	2.x	2020	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
RTC, SVN, Gitlab.			
Windows XP/7 and LINUX.			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

1/22/2021 $https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=b9701a02158f654d775437807c8a4e67595e5d0548415a450514440c5\dots\\$

English	Proficient
Hindi	Beginner
Kannada	Expert
Telugu	Beginner

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time